<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radio on Climate and Society</title>
    <link>/tags/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in radio on Climate and Society</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Take on an Old Tradition</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/oysters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/oysters/</guid>
      <description>Oysters are an icon of Cape Cod. Tourists flock here in the summer to find the best shellfish in town, enjoy evenings at oyster bars, and even try their hand at oyster picking themselves. But the Falmouth Municipal Shellfish Propagation Program is giving these small animals a whole new life here, growing them to both control pollution and bolster local aquaculture industry.
   Christina Lovely of Falmouth Marine and Environmental Services at the Waquoit Bay field site   Falmouth’s nitrogen pollution problem is becoming worse as the population here grows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A River Reborn</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/coonamessett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/coonamessett/</guid>
      <description>The story of the Coonamessett river in Cape Cod could have been one of a group of humans dismantling a natural environment. In the last three centuries, the Coonamessett has been profoundly modified. First, by the creation of dams blocking the river done by the grist mill industry. Later, by the sanding of the river for growing cranberries. However, this isn’t just a story about how people managed to disrupt a nice flowing river so badly that all that was left was a bunch of scattered ponds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking Carbon</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/carbon-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/carbon-bank/</guid>
      <description>On the southern shore of Cape Cod you can find beautiful, bright green marshlands within Waquoit Bay. The marshes are homes for a vast array of plants and animals that rely on them to survive. Although, due to climate change their homes are being altered by storms, sea-level rise, and ocean acidification which leads to vegetation loss and a decline of various birds species. Some people may be unaware of the importance of marine marshes and how they are powerful natural ecosystems with potential to reduce climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Inscription</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/black-inscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/black-inscription/</guid>
      <description>As the science of climate change has painted an increasingly dire picture of the near future, the importance of environmental communication has become a hot topic in the environmental movement. While the main takeaways of climate science and the reality of global warming caused by human activities are all but entirely settled, people often aren’t able to fully internalize what this means on a personal level.
  Visuals projected during the recent performance of Black Inscription      Matthias Bossi and Carla Kihlstedt during rehursals   In Woods Hole, a center of oceanographic studies, a local musical and multimedia performance called Black Inscription took on the challenge of communicating these tough scientific lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Bridges Over Warming Waters</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/ocean-heat-waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/ocean-heat-waves/</guid>
      <description>This summer, fisherman on the cape encountered a surprising catch. Traps hauled aboard were full of lifeless lobsters. Upon further investigation, this die-off was attributed to changes in the ocean’s temperature, more specifically, an ocean heat wave.
   Visitors are hard pressed to find a local menu without seafood options     Dr. Glen Gawarkiewicz is a senior scientist at Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution    But this is more than just a story about ocean heat waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echos of the End</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/right-whales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/right-whales/</guid>
      <description>Everybody enjoys peace and quiet. It gives us the ability to have a quiet conversation, to clear the mind, and to focus. At times it can be hard to find this silence, but once the sound is drowned out relief is found.
   The North Atlantic Right Whale feeding   For some people their quiet place may be the sea, a place where waves gently land on silky shores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Nitrogen</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/wastewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/wastewater/</guid>
      <description>The local wastewater treatment plant probably isn’t the first place you’d choose to spend a Saturday afternoon. But as algal blooms devoured the oxygen in Falmouth’s ponds and the fish floated belly-up, the coastal town’s idyllic waters started to smell worse than the treatment plant. A day with the wastewater might not seem so bad after all.
   Amy Lowell, Falmouth Wastewater Superintendent, explains nitrogen removal at the treatment plant   Decades-long resistance to sewering in Falmouth meant the town continued to depend on residential septic systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shells Under Threat</title>
      <link>/ec_stories/shell-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ec_stories/shell-day/</guid>
      <description>Ocean Acidification is a progressing issue in the face of climate change. Jenny Rheuben is a Research Associate with the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution who focuses on the effects of climate change on coastal environments. Here, Rhueban speaks to the threat of ocean acidification, an example of how climate change impacts our natural resources and how people are in turn affected by that.
   Jenny Rheuben is a Research Associate at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution   While addressing the threat of ocean acidification, we must first be able to monitor it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>