<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Climate and Society</title>
    <link>/climateandsociety/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Climate and Society</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/climateandsociety/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/amalia-and-sarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/amalia-and-sarah/</guid>
      <description>“We enjoyed meeting Betsy Gladfelter, she was a great interviewee and inspiring to us. The whole process of producing the podcast was enjoyable. We had a good brainstorming stage, a great interview and a story that flowed naturally. Our biggest challenge was reducing a fantastic audio of several hours full of incredible details to a five-minute podcast. This experience gave us a better idea of what producing radio is like, an exercise for attempting to produce a story suitable for a non-scientific audience and a close-up to the different and complex steps that take place in a restoration process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/amelia-and-nicole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/amelia-and-nicole/</guid>
      <description>“We enjoyed the creative freedom that we had within our story, which gave us the opportunity to keep reconstructing our narrative until we came to a final product. One challenge we would like to highlight is that Amelia doesn’t have a Mac, which meant that more work had to be done on Nicole’s computer, and if we had to work on something after class, Nicole would always need to be there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/derek-and-natalie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/derek-and-natalie/</guid>
      <description>“We enjoyed interviewing the most out of all the tasks. Connecting with our interview subject like that was incredibly rewarding and fun and got us out of our comfort zone. Also, we learned a lot from her and felt incredibly connected to the scientific community. The most challenging part was the audio organization. Going through all the quotes and picking the best ones was also a challenge because we got so many strong ones that would have added to the story immensely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/dylan-and-george/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/dylan-and-george/</guid>
      <description>“This was a very rewarding project to work on. From tip to tail, interview to editing, we found it fun, interesting, and personal. Carla and Matthias were a joy to interview and it meant a lot that we felt we had made a genuine connection. Most of the groundwork was in writing the script, and it was a new experience that took a lot of collaboration. It was a fun and fulfilling way to get to know each other throughout the semester, and we’re proud of what we did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/jessie-and-rachel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/jessie-and-rachel/</guid>
      <description>“Overall, our favorite part of this process was talking with our interviewees. Both Glen and Mark had such interesting perspectives on the partnership, as well as on the human role in learning about and caring for the oceans. A challenge we faced was “murdering our darlings” as we wrote the script. Often, we’d get attached to ideas or quotes that we had our hearts set on including, and cutting them out of the final script was so difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/maia-and-mujahed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/maia-and-mujahed/</guid>
      <description>“Our team enjoyed learning about new ways to save the environment and reduce the impacts of climate change. It is inspiring to know how many passionate scientists have chosen to take action in the Cape Cod area by protecting marshlands instead of simply waiting for the public to react. We also enjoyed learning about the interviewing process, collecting sounds and footage, and editing the soundtracks and videos later. One of our challenges was adjusting to the meeting time changes with our interviewees; it was important to be flexible during the interview process and use time wisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/mathilde-and-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/mathilde-and-june/</guid>
      <description>“We truly enjoyed learning how to operate the recording tools and heading over to WHOI to interview Jenny Rheuben. It was a joy working together, but that’s not to say that developing our story didn’t have a couple bumps in the road. Our original story excited us and we had set a distinct path that we’d like to follow, but the information we got from the interview lead us in a different direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/climateandsociety/authors/naomi-and-mollie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/climateandsociety/authors/naomi-and-mollie/</guid>
      <description>“We came into this project with a set direction that we wanted our story to go in, but after a change in interview subject and learning more about the Municipal Shellfish Program, we reworked our story and found it to be much richer. Lots of parts of this process were new to us and we of course learned a lot about oysters and aquaculture on Cape Cod, as well as how to produce a podcast or radio segment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>